Contact

ritchellern@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/drritchelle-broadnax-dnp-crnp-fnpc-34907753 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nurse Practitioners Clinical Research Board Certified

Dr. Ritchelle Broadnax DNP, CRNP,FNP-C

Family Nurse Practitioner/ Hospitalist

Montgomery, Alabama Area

Summary

Experienced Chronic and Post Acute Care Nurse Practitioner with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital, nursing home,home health & travel nurse industry. Skilled in Nursing Education, Critical Care Nursing, and Healthcare Management. Strong healthcare services professional with a Doctorate of Nursing focused in Family Nurse Practitioner from University of Alabama.

Experience

Broadnax Healthcare LLC
Business Owner
August 2019 - Present (1 year)
Birmingham, Alabama

Offering telemedicine, video visits with prescriptions sent to pharmacy as well as office visits in the Birmingham area.

Cigna Insurance Services
Nurse Practitioner
May 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)
Alabama

Performing 360 head to toe assessment and closing healthcare gaps on patients with Cigna Healthsprings insurance plans

TeamHealth

Post Acute Care Nurse Practitioner February 2018 - August 2019 (1 year 7 months) Montgomery, Alabama

Primary Provider for 90 SIMPRA patients in Long term care facility. Focus is on in house treatment and low hospitalization rate. Managing chronic and acute illnesses, post hospitalization care, prescribing medications and pain management

Arlington clinic Nurse Practitioner March 2015 - July 2018 (3 years 5 months) Birmingham, Alabama

Arlington Clinic
Internal Medicine practice

LHI Communications
Nurse Practitioner
August 2017 - February 2018 (7 months)
Montgomery, Alabama

Performed Veteran exams used in determining eligibility of post service benefits

Woundtech Wound Care NP November 2017 - January 2018 (3 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

3 month contract with Staff Care treating worsening or non healing wounds referred from hospitals and home health. Serviced Huntington Beach and Pasadena area.

ATC Healthcare Contract nurse June 1998 - November 2017 (19 years 6 months) Birmingham,AL

School nurse, flu shot clinic, BCBS preexisting condition screening, homehealth nurse, occupational health, med/surg, hospice care

Greystone Neurology and Pain Management Nurse Practitioner July 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 4 months)

Prescribed Narcotics for acute and chronic pain. Performed joint and trigger point injections.

St. Vincent's Health System
Hospitalist
January 2016 - July 2016 (7 months)

Wallace State Community College Clinical Instructor

Page 2 of 3

December 2014 - February 2016 (1 year 3 months)

Hanceville, Alabama

Clinical instructor for RN students

Nephrology

CRNP

December 2008 - January 2015 (6 years 2 months)

US Navy

Meteorologist

May 1994 - May 1997 (3 years 1 month)

Rota Naval, Andalucia, Spain

Presented weather briefings for Airforce and Navy pilots

Education

University of Alabama

Doctorate of Nursing, Family Nurse Practitioner · (2014 - 2016)

Troy University

MSN, Family Nurse Practitioner · (2012 - 2014)

Jacksonville State University

Bachelor's degree, Nursing · (2011 - 2012)

George C Wallace State Community College-Selma

Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2000 - 2001)